DOCTOR X: MAFIA IN WHITE
EPISODE 1
Hey, how much does
tangsuyuk cost nowadays anyway?
At this rate,
when are you gonna pay all your debts down
and let yourself work independently?
There we go!
- That's it! That's what I like to see!
- Good lord.
I can't stop winning!
Dude, holy shit, they're playing
so freaking loud over there.
Hey, sir! Come change these lights out.
Damn it!
Wanna give it a shot? Want me to
clean you out? Down to your underwear?
Oh, man,
not even I could wear ones that gigantic.
Hey, Mister!
Can we please get a tangsuyuk and jjajang?
Okay, I see you.
We'll take a double-order.
- How have you been?
- Would you like a refill?
My, my, my, a doctor elected as mayor.
Congrats to you Mayor,
from the president of the KMA.
Oh, it was all because of you, Mister Kim.
I truly appreciate your hard work.
Come on, please!
Are you forgetting anybody?
I, Kim Myeong-seop, the Director,
of Guseo University Medical Center,
aided you, right, Mr. Mayor?
Oh, my goodness, how could
I ever forget about you, Director Kim?
Congratulations, Mayor,
I wish the best to you.
Mm.
Thank you.
Hey! Good Lord, you're pouring
all that wine like it's soju. Relax!
It's a lot of congrats there.
- Mayor Im Ho-seok.
- Yes?
That's Doctor Do Yun-sik, from GUMC.
Wow, my goodness! Hello! I enjoyed
your latest paper, excellent read.
You're exceptional when it comes
to clinical research.
Well, I have to say, it's all\
thanks to Director Kim and Chairman Gu.
- Hey, pour me some, too.
- Sure.
- Not too much for me.
- Okay.
- Chairman, Jeong Kwon, nice to meet you.
- Hello.
Chairman, I'm Kim Gwang-hyeon,
nice to meet you.
Chairman, I'm Lee Gyeong-seok,
Hey, you should go into plastic surgery
or dermatology. Why general surgery?
- Oh, ophthalmology could work.
- Leave him alone.
Having a surgeon we know
will come in handy when we're older.
You think you would like orthopedics?
By that logic, wouldn't
internal medicine be better?
Ugh, I didn't go to med school
just to care for you guys.
I understand. It was to be able
to inherit the hospital.
Ugh. Just focus on the ball,
you little shit.
Hmm-hmm.
- What're you doing? Some kinda pervert?
- Oh, man, that hurts...
Nah, I hit myself with the cue earlier.
Hey, I'm gonna hit the bathroom.
Hurry back.
Ah! Ah!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. What's wrong? Hey!
- It hurts!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
- Mister, hey, get a hold of yourself.
Uh, wh- where's the pain?
Where's it hurting?
Here, here, here. Here, here, here...
Is it swollen?
What organ would that be there?
Oh... Oh... Ah!
You also a doctor?
Just- Well, actually, I'm just an intern.
He should stand. Come on.
Uh... yeah- okay. Uh, I- I'll pick him up.
- It hurts!
- You're okay, you're okay.
It hurts.
I'm gonna have to disrobe him.
You're doing what, lady?
What're you, insane?
- You want your friend to die?
- Ah, shit...
Cough for me, sir.
Tighten your stomach.
Now, cough.
It's a left inguinal hernia.
I performed a manual reduction.
Ah! It was a left inguinal hernia.
There's a risk of recurrence,
the patient needs an emergency operation.
Aren't you a doctor?
I think you should come with us.
Wait, I'm only an intern, I told you!
Hey, wait! Wait a second.
What's your name?
Can you tell me who you are?
Together, we've weathered
the COVID-nineteen pandemic,
the legislation mandating cameras
in operating rooms,
and even the strike against
increasing medical school admissions.
We fought desperately through all of those
challenging, turbulent periods.
But the crisis isn't over.
Inside, we're battling the union.
Outside, changes to
the Medical Service Act.
Meanwhile, doctors are called frauds
by a crooked media.
Doctors must be protected
for healthcare to function.
However, those-
those dolts are just unable
to comprehend that.
That's why, today...
it's important that we at Magnolia
stand in complete harmony.
Our fellow Magnolia member,
Im Ho-seok's election as mayor...
is only the beginning.
Let's hear it! Let's hear it! Yeah!
Alright, alright.
I swear I will never forget where I began,
you have my word,
I swear on my white coat.
Nor will I ever forget Magnolia,
and the support I was given by it,
in the journey toward where I am.
And with that said...
Hear, hear! To the white coats!
To the white coats!
We have how many letters of resignation?
Ugh, this is killing me, I can't take it.
He really isn't responding?
Oh, hey, I gotta go.
Uh, why are you out here, sir?
You're working hard.
Come on, please, now. Sit down.
I'm going to the toilet. So, why don't you
let me head to men's room?
Ah, I'd watch it with the wine, sir.
The patients are who we need to worry for,
you sons of bitches.
And I hope you all get gout from
stuffing your faces with all that meat.
God, at this point, is there even
a doctor left worth seeing?
Self-centered assholes.
Whoa, this is so awesome.
This is my first time going to the ER
after a manual reduction. Whoa...
You know, I can't say I've seen
something like this either. Weird...
Uh, wait! Wait- Wait a second.
What's your name?
Can you tell me who you are?
Huh?
What was that?
Wait, what's that supposed to mean?
Hey, you didn't say who you are! Hold on!
119 EMS
The White Tower is collapsing.
Hospitals nationwide were repeatedly
devastated by the COVID-19 pandemic,
the passing of laws mandating
cameras in operating rooms,
and strikes over
medical school enrollment quotas.
DURING CONSTRUCTION,
DEPARTMENTS WILL SHARE A STAFF ROOM
Construction on that started so long ago.
Doesn't seem like
they've gotten anything done.
Ah, shit!
In response, the government proposed
a half-baked, purely symbolic bill,
and doctors responded by
leaving the hospitals in droves.
The patients have been
completely sidelined in this fight.
Doctors started it, and now nurses.
It's tough enough being a general surgeon,
how did things things get so messed up?
- I'm sorry, sir.
- Yes, sir, I'm sorry.
I'm making rounds
for the first time in eons, today.
This is humiliating.
And the OR? Who's over there?
Well, sir, I...
Given the urgency and timing,
I did call someone in, to...
temporarily assist today.
GUSEO UNIVERSITY SEONAM MEDICAL CENTER
And...
a new kind of doctor entered the arena.
A doctor who belongs to no group.
It's nice to meet you!
I'm your surgical intern, Park Tae-gyeong.
I'm glad to be working with you!
Excuse me, am I late?
Uh, I shouldn't be.
Sir, hi, good morning.
May I please ask you...
Morning, how are you? I'm Ma Seong-gyu,
I'm your senior resident.
You'll be valuable to the team,
but I'm too busy to show it,
'cause, suddenly, Director Kim
has decided to make the rounds,
which means you're gonna need
to get out there, right now, too.
So, your seat is, umm...
Well, you'll be in surgery,
so it doesn't matter.
You can just, uh... sit wherever. Yeah.
Oh, but that doesn't mean
you should quit this week.
- What are you doing, intern?
- Sorry?
Ah, rounds.
Yes, sir!
Director Kim Myeong-seop
will now begin to make his rounds.
A freelance doctor
unaffiliated with any medical institution,
also known as a mercenary doctor.
This story, at its deepest point,
is the story of the wolf.
A solitary figure who emerged
in the era of the mafia in white,
in which medicine, where life hangs in the
balance, is driven by money and power.
The person that you see before you
flies in the face of authority
and refuses to be bound to anyone.
The only weapons she keeps
in her arsenal are her medical license
and the surgical skills
she sharpened from bare metal.
Gye Su-jeong, general surgeon.
Also known as... Doctor X.
I haven't had a moment to look
through all your paperwork yet.
Your name? First and last.
Gye Su-jeong.
"Gye", you said? That's your name?
Later today, we're holding
a conference to review an operation,
so you should attend that first.
- Hey, you- Wha-
- Ah, Doctor Gye?
When Dr. Do talks to you, you answer.
- Dr. Do, Director Kim's waiting for you..
- Oh, my. Let's go.
Wow, looks like Director Kim
is really all in on this surgery.
He's even attending
the conference himself.
Well, given that his retirement
is just around the corner,
I suppose he's pretty excited
he gets to do it.
Please stand.
THE 7TH MEDICAL STAFF CONFERENCE
Be seated.
Um... we're ready,
the conference will now begin.
The patient is Seo Byeong-gyu,
an 80-year-old male.
Findings suggest gallbladder cancer,
he's scheduled for open cholecystectomy.
At the direct insistence of the patient,
Director Kim Myeong-seop
will serve as the surgeon
and handle the procedure personally.
In light of that, the process that
Director Kim has created and pioneered,
the MS technique, will be applied.
It is a legendary technique
and a surgical standard for 30 years.
And this will serve as our opportunity
to witness it in person.
The "MS technique"?
Whatever, it's just open surgery.
This operation is likely my last chance
to remind myself that I'm a surgeon.
Don't say that, please, Mister Director!
As I take on this surgery,
I will do the best for my patient
and their health.
Allow Dr. Bae and Dr. Ma
to assist you in the operation, Director.
I look forward to learning from you.
And now, aside from these two,
anyone else who is available
should observe it as well.
- Thank you very much, Director Kim.
Yeah, I object.
Who is that?
Hold on a minute, is that
the temp from the locum tenens agency?
So, is she their ace?
Temp doc? Ace?
- She's...
- What are you talking about?
There you go. Our intern knows what's up.
An ace? Yeah, right.
An "X", more like. An "X".
Is there a reason to go this route?
Do we have to do it open?
Why would you open him up?
Laparoscopic cholecystectomy
has long been standard practice
for a durable post-surgery result
and quicker recovery.
If you open him up, the patient
will be hospitalized for at least 10 days,
and it'll be harder on his body.
So why insist on doing it
with greater risk?
Director, I apologize.
She's a temp doctor that the hospital
brought in today, she doesn't know what--
I'll grant you this, we rely on
machines a lot these days,
and that's all good.
In fact, Doctor Heung-gon is known
for his laparoscopic surgeries,
so he knows better than any other doctor.
Luckily, this case
happens to be very fortunate
as the cancer was detected in this patient
at a routine ultrasound, without symptoms.
However, we're all aware
it's hard to distinguish between
abdominal inflammation
and gallbladder cancer with imaging
when up against the possibility
for cancer to become metastatic,
if we suspect even
the tiniest risk of cancer,
we need surgery to excise all the cancer
instead of relying on
a less invasive approach.
Isn't that right, Doctor Bae?
Yes, Director, that's right.
Open surgery has several advantages
compared to a laparoscopic procedure,
in removing the tumors
from the gallbladder and-
As you said,
this is such a fortunate case.
the ultrasound identified
the cancer early,
an early-stage gallbladder cancer
has a high survival rate,
so the procedure selected
should factor in the patient's condition.
The patient's 80. He had pneumonia three
years ago from complications of COVID-19.
We can remove cancer
with a laparoscopic operation,
send it for biopsy and, based on results,
proceed with open surgery.
She's one smart cookie.
That's a call for the surgeon to make!
A surgeon needs the ability to touch
and see the surgical site directly,
so that they can handle
adhesions or bleeding,
remove the disease
at the source, directly,
as extensively and deeply as possible,
in order to ensure the patient's safety.
This is the best way,
the most reliable process there is,
to save a life!
- Well said, Director!
- I agree with that.
Looks like...
maybe you're excited because you've been
booked for the first time in decades.
What? "Booked"?
How could you use such
a colloquial word toward the Director?
Oh, instead of "booked", I'll say, uh...
Selected by anyone?
"Selected by anyone"?
How dare you speak to Director Kim
as if he's not a legend?
I think you should
be honest about it, sir.
You haven't been selected
by a patient in years,
you wanna operate, but you don't know
how to do the surgery laparoscopically.
Aren't you just
suggesting outdated theories
so you can try and make
your decision sound convincing?
If these people do have medical licenses,
and follow the ethics they're supposed to,
they'd likely agree that a laparoscopic
specialist should perform the surgery.
And I bet that laparoscopic specialist
would agree as well.
What was that? I wouldn't say that.
I swear, Director Kim, that's not true,
I don't think that at all.
Enough already. Please tell me
what are you trying to do here?
What I wanna say, is... uh...
Here, I'll put it less colloquially, then.
Ah!
That'd fit the occasion better.
You are acting greedy... for your age.
Oh, Mister Director...
Get out!
Get her out! What're you waiting for?
Please, sit down.
Oh, my goodness.
Wow. She's extraordinary.
Listen, Miss Jang, that temp
dog of yours you sent me is insane.
Not "dog", "doc"!
She's not a dog, a person, that-
Gye Su-jeong, the surgeon!
What is the matter with her?
My goodness, is that so?
Oh, it certainly seems Doctor Gye Su-jeong
behaved rather inappropriately.
DIRECTOR JANG'S LOCUM TENENS AGENCY
Oh, I'm sorry, forgive me.
She can be pretty sharp-tongued.
SU-JEONG, FEB. 9: FIRST DAY AT GUMC
Ah. Nonetheless, her surgical skills
are far beyond doubt,
so I'm sure she'll be of
great help to your hospital.
Uh, given everything that happened,
I'll give you a discount for the month.
How does that sound?
Yes, of course, I'll ensure she
stays in check now, don't worry.
Uh-huh.
Thank you for working with us.
You take care, now. Mmm.
- I go now, right?
- She caused another issue?
She just said what she had to, that's all.
Ah, here!
Advance one space.
Oh. This shoulder hurts,
do some acupuncture, quick.
- And will you pay me up front?
- I'll even cook some grub for you.
Grub? Whoa, I'm up for some grub.
- Let's go. One, two, three, four, five.
- No, no... see, I can't let that happen.
Landed on Seoul.
Oh, man. Come on, not Seoul...
When I heard it was gallbladder cancer,
everything froze over.
As if everything around me, just...
After hearing that, I recalled years ago
I saw you on television, talking about it.
And seeing that, I thought to myself,
"Gallbladder cancer must be dangerous
if they have this doctor on television."
Oh, yes, that was-
Oh, the DBS show, it's the
Secrets of Life and Death:
The Master of Gallbladder Cancer,
Kim Myung-seop Special.
Oh, Director, it's truly an honor for us.
As fate would have it, actually,
through my factory,
I've manufactured and supplied gloves
to this hospital for over 20 years.
Of course,
I also supply to other hospitals as well.
But still, I've always taken pride
in supplying to this...
- Mm. Please sign this form, here.
- Ah, okay.
- Director Kim has other patients to see.
- So sorry for holding you up. I apologise.
Ah, there's one other thing...
- a small token of our appreciation.
- Oh-ho-ho! So kind.
I could get in trouble
if I were to take that gift.
Oh, please do take it, Director.
Honestly, we just wouldn't feel right
unless we could properly give our thanks.
We insist on it, sir.
Please take our gift, Director Kim.
Yes, Director. Thank you very much.
Uh, Director Kim,
the update should be done soon.
Can I help with
anything else you might need?
No.
- Get back to work when it's done.
- Yes, sir, will do.
Good grief. Ugh!
Uh, Director, I'm done with the update.
Get this out of here.
- empty that trash can while you're at it!
- Yes, thank you, we will.
"Thanks for everything."
What did I thank him for?
What do you got?
Ah, it's jocheong, actually.
Jocheong? Okay. That stuff's like honey?
I think it's homemade, with how it looks.
The ones at the store aren't this color.
How do you know all that?
Oh, my grandma'd always make some for me
when I'd go and visit during the holidays.
She made some for me when
I took the CSAT to wish me good luck,
and she promised me she'd make some
when I took the medical licensing exam,
but she passed two years ago.
Okay, well, you should have it.
You gotta stir the pot all night
to make the amount that we have here.
You should try a little bit, at least.
She must've really worked hard on it.
She made it for him
with a lot of gratitude.
So, you're a "gimme a thousand
paper cranes" type of guy?
What?
It's nothing,
just take care of those two, okay?
Alright.
RESUME
I genuinely think that
it's justified to fire her right away.
The level of disrespect
that that lady showed...
I got the consent for the surgery
and updated his files and computer.
Good work, thank you.
- Dr. Do. Well?
- Hm?
I got it. Take a read.
"Gye Su-jeong."
So that temp woman,
her name is Gye Su-jeong?
Man, she looks like
she's older than I thought.
She went to Cubanacan University
and Florida College of Medicine.
Look below that.
She returned after doing volunteer work
in remote areas around the world.
She holds a GS and CS, also...
She's done quite a bit for her age,
I'll give her that.
Wow, she's sick.
Doctor Bae here is double-board certified
in both NS and GS, this is nothing.
"After returning, registered with
Locum Tenens Agency as a general surgeon."
And... "Hobby, surgery.
Special skills, surgery."
She put surgery down for all her answers.
Seems like a fraud.
- You're sure you want her here?
- Do some more research.
With that strong of a résumé,
why would she wanna freelance here?
What's wrong with us, huh?
What's wrong with this hospital?
That isn't what I meant to say...
Hey, Gye Su,
for the time being, assist Doctors Ma
and Park, that's where we need you.
Doctor Su-jeong.
Assist them with what, Doctor?
What do you mean, with what?
You're gonna follow these two
on their rounds.
Let's start with prepping
for the conference.
I think we're done.
What're you gonna do with her?
We're short on specialized surgeons.
It's free, so we'll keep her for the week.
And because we're nice.
Look, we'll just keep her at her desk
so Director Kim can't see her.
SEO BYEONG-GYU, MALE/80 C24
MALIGNANT NEOPLASM OF BILIARY TRACT
Sorry, I, uh...
That inguinal hernia patient that day?
I was at the pool hall with you.
Remember that?
Man, your diagnosis that day was spot on,
and thanks to you, he was able
to have a successful operation.
Although, uhm...
how come at the end, you made an "X"?
What do people draw an "X" to get across?
Uhm, well...
I guess to say, "no", or "can't be done"?
Well, then you know.
Meaning, "you... are not it."
Or, "you can't do anything"?
So you don't think I have what it takes?
Wait, why, though?
Why don't- Why don't I?
Why did you give me an "X"?
I don't remember telling you to look
at Mister Seo Byeong-gyu's chart.
He runs a rubber factory.
That's right, we actually get our
surgical gloves from his factory, as well.
- He seemed very proud to be our supplier.
- Just do the work I assigned you.
If you were him, would you want
the Director to operate on you?
Huh?
Well, you're a doctor too, so you know
this isn't the right thing to do.
I consider that matter addressed
at the conference earlier.
Then, would you want him to?
- Yes, of course.
- Then...
what if it were your parents?
If it wasn't you who needed surgery.
How about your mother?
Uh, do- do we really
need to make it so personal?
Because, as it happens,
this patient has a child, too.
They're not just a doctor.
I'd pick the Director.
My mother would let Director Kim
operate on her, and as a matter of fact,
say I was actually the patient
and had a child of my own,
I'd feel all the more willing
for the Director to handle my operation,
if anything,
for the sake of my child's future.
Hey, can you clean up this chart quickly,
and send it back to me.
- Ah, yes, sir. Will do.
- Hm.
- What's going on?
- Doctor Bae, I'm so glad that you're here.
This is exactly the reason
I don't like any of you people.
What? What did you say?
"You people"? What'd you say? Huh?
- I think you must've misheard , Dr. Bae.
- He heard it right. That's what I said.
- Hey.
- It's people like you...
that I don't like at all.
People who did nothing but study just
to make good money and get ahead.
You're intelligent in the stupidest way,
with no convictions or ethics of your own.
You grovel in front of attendings, but
hold your heads high in front of patients.
You flatter your attendings,
but treat nurses like shit.
You ignore corruption above you,
but say the system's why you're corrupt.
You only care about your own convenience,
you're fine entrusting
a patient's surgery to that dinosaur
who can barely manage his own health
or keep his surgical skills up to date
- you'd be lucky if he kept a steady hand.
- Hey, you shut your mouth, that's en-
You complacent people, who despite knowing
the suffering the patient will undertake,
that a life is at stake, turn a blind eye,
all you think of is how you get off easy.
You people,
who think it's normal for patients
even elderly patients,
to beg for a life-or-death surgery,
while thanking you
for doing what you should.
People...
that aren't anything more than doctors.
Yeah.
You guys are the lowest of the low.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Get out, right now!
- I- I can-
- Get out.
- Get out, I mean it!
- Get out!
What are you looking at?
What's up, you wanna go? Huh?
Fine, come at me.
- Come, try me.
- Oh no, what is this?
What? You gonna
throw that little sack? Huh?
Six o'clock!
Yeah, that's right.
- Run away, get out!
- Oh.
Why "oh"?
What? Don't tell me...
Did she just clock out?
You, go get her back,
we gotta get her back, let's go.
- Yes, sir.
- Bring her back here, right now.
Damn it. Who's she think she is,
clocking out and walking out that way?
ROOM 4210 SEO ******-GYU
- My goodness. Oh my, just as I thought.
- Hello.
I'm glad we picked the Director
to handle things.
All the doctors have been
taking turns checking on us.
- Oh, was another doctor here to see you?
- Yes.
- Actually, it was just a little while ago.
- Ah.
Here. Oh, here,
you should have some mango too.
Our daughter got them for us
when she stopped by
to perk up her dad,
since he'll have to fast for his surgery.
- Have some.
- It's extra sweet, so look out.
The doctor who stopped by earlier
had some mango, and enjoyed it too.
Mm, you gave the doctor
a little yogurt too, right?
Yes, of course.
Ah, actually, I think they
might've been a doctor.
Did you see their name?
We have it on our coat.
No, this doctor didn't
have their white coat on.
Although, she said she was a doctor.
- It was a woman, is what you're saying?
- That's right.
Ah, it's just... she said something odd.
- She said we should delay the surgery.
- Oh, well...
Is Director Kim alright?
Is there anything that we should know?
Oh, no, he's great! Uh, did she happen
to tell you a reason, or was that every-
Oh, I said, "No,
because of the factory, we can't delay."
Then she asked if I'd let
another doctor do the operation,
I said, "I don't want anyone else.
"I absolutely require Director Kim,
exactly as I'd picked, only he can do it."
Ah... I think she was just curious.
I can assure you, your surgery
will go great tomorrow.
- Ah, well, alright. Thank you very much.
- Of course.
Ah, thanks so much for this.
- Rest up.
- Let's try this first.
- Still,
It's the largest hospital
in the Seoul metro area,
but they're less meddlesome
than in Seoul itself.
They're a little shadier, so it's easier
to squeeze money out of 'em,
and for us, that's a win.
I think you mean
it's a win for you, actually, huh?
Su-jeong...
you shouldn't forget to breathe
while you're eating.
You should also be taking shorter showers.
The gas bill went up again.
Well, I pay everything I owe.
So, about the director.
Who? Kim Myeong-seop?
You know anything about him?
You wanna know, I'll charge you.
It'll come out of your check.
My goodness, you're as ruthless
as they say you are, aren't you?
And, hey, get some more in there.
Hey, who cooked this?
Director Kim, we would like to say sorry
that we're late sending our regards.
There's no need to say sorry.
Usually, we only give this to people
who sign a contract with us, but...
Director Kim, allow us to
make our amends through this.
Ah... is this... your signature gift?
Your famous melon box you gift to clients?
Goodness, well, your recognizing it
is most appreciated.
- I left its contents with your secretary.
- Ah, I see. Uh... mm...
Uh... as you know, Mister Director,
you hold on to the box.
Ah, okay... ah.
Ah, my goodness, this melon just looks
like the most delicious thing, eh?
The best. I choose
the highest-quality melons, Director.
It's imported as well,
so it's quite some trouble to get.
I see.
Now, Director, Doctor Gye Su-jeong
has spent many years outside of Korea.
She's not used to Korean hospital culture.
She acted out of turn because she's
unfamiliar with your illustrious legacy.
Please give her another chance.
All right.
Doctor Gye has much
left to learn, I would say.
Please, just keep her around
and have her do menial tasks.
She just doesn't know
any better, that's all.
I also will be coming to
see you operate today, as well.
Oh... really?
Yes, the MS technique would be amazing...
to witness in an OR with my own eyes.
Alright.
I'll allow you to come.
Thank you, Director.
I feel the need to say, it's been
a long time since he's held a scalpel,
and there'll be
a million eyes watching this.
I'll cover if he makes any mistakes.
But without Director Kim knowing, got it?
You got it. Understood, sir.
Didn't Doctor Gye come in
to work this morning?
Don't ask me that this early
ahead of an operation, it's bad luck.
I didn't realize that simple
a question could be so touchy.
You always have
to have the last word, don't you?
Oh, I'll make sure you have the last word
as we keep working together.
You know what you're doing, you little-
Oh, Doctor, you're here!
We're so glad to see you.
I heard Director Kim
asked you to attend today.
It sure has been a while.
It really is nice to see you, Doctor Bu.
How d'you like it over there?
Surely you're doing well.
I'm... just doing my best.
Oh, you're also here.
Well, what a shock.
I mean, what a surprise Doctor Bu
blocked the time to watch the Director.
I've heard stories that, supposedly,
he was to be the main hospital's Director,
but then he got passed over, after that
they put him in the south branch.
How upsetting.
Gosh, how cruel, I had no idea.
And, how come he was
passed over for Director?
Well, he's no fun,
and, to his credit,
way too good a doctor.
In the Doctor community,
he's not the most well-liked among them.
Hmm... mm.
If I take your word for it, he's no fun,
I guess, more ways than just the one.
No, not those. Bring me the powdered ones.
- Sorry?
- Those make my hands sweat too much.
Yes, we have them ready for you.
Ah... right.
Nothing of note happened during induction,
and his vitals are stable, Director.
Finally, we'll have your
legendary surgery on record.
Today's the first time
I've seen an upside to those cameras.
There's no need to be nervous.
I'll just do what I always do.
That's Doctor Bae for you.
Let me tell you, back in the day,
I removed two gallbladders at once
listening to this, using my own technique.
Turn up the volume.
I can't hear the monitor, Director.
Turn it down a bit.
Okay... let's get started.
We'll now begin the cholecystectomy
for Seo Byeong-gyu,
performed by Director Kim Myeong-seop.
- Let's do our best.
Scalpel.
I swear, I warned him not to hand it
to the Director until he asked.
Isn't it convenient to pass it to him
without him even needing to ask, though?
No, he doesn't see it that way.
For him, it’s a case of,
"How dare a mere nurse step out of line?"
Back in his day,
he brought quite a few nurses to tears.
What kind of asshole would do that?
Ah, yes, I'm sure.
I can certainly figure that he did.
Do not.
It's not too late to stop the operation
and take him for an MRI.
What? Why would the patient need an MRI?
No, not the patient. The Director.
What kind of nonsense is this?
What're you on?
You're gonna get kicked out,
like the conference?
Oh, dear. Doctor Gye,
my goodness, you're rare today.
Let's go over here, come here, Doctor Gye.
Let it play out a little longer.
This could be fun to watch, hmm?
Who turned down the volume?
Let's go, wipe already!
MS forceps.
These forceps here were designed
for the technique named after me.
In my heyday, I used these to do
more than four surgeries a day.
That's incredible.
Mm. Once this surgery's done, I'll give
them to you to look after from now on.
Oh, it would be an honor.
Experienced surgeons arey able to handle
10 surgeries a day, in their prime.
Well, he's slow as shit.
Wipe.
Look at this.
As expected, severe adhesion
due to recurring inflammation.
Opening him up was the right call, huh?
Hmm.
MS forceps.
Look at this.
See how elegantly it grabs on.
Right angle.
Oh!
What are you doing?
Sweat keeps getting in my eyes!
Right angle.
Metz.
Blood pressure's dropping,
systolic below 60, heart rate's over 150.
Vitals are unstable.
He's in shock. I'll give him some fluids.
- Director?
- Director, what should we...
Dir... Director,
you need to pull your mask up.
- Director?
- Director, are you okay?
Director?
- What's happening?
- Is he alright?
Director! Director,
you need to wake up. Director!
Director. Director?
Squeeze my hand, sir. Squeeze my hand.
- Is he alright?
- Director's losing consciousness.
It looks like he's paralyzed
on his left side!
I suspect a CVA or a cerebral infarction.
- Run a CT, now!
- Bring a stretcher!
Vitals unstable. Risk of contamination.
Clear everything out now.
Uh, secure an IV line for Director Kim,
and give him some fluids, hurry!
Call neurosurgery!
No, wait, Doctor Bae, stay with him!
- I'll be right there!
- Okay!
One, two, three.
What are you going to do
about this patient? He's in shock!
Get in here, quick!
What are you going to do
about this patient?
Doctor Bae Heung-gon, Doctor Ma Seong-gyu!
- Come on, hurry, hurry, hurry!
- What are we supposed to do if you leave?
Wait, what about the patient?
You stay back here for now.
You take care of him.
What? Where are you... Dr. Bae?
Ma Seong-gyu!
Hey!
Hey. Doctor Jo. Uh- w-what do we do?
I'll keep him stable for now.
Go page someone.
Everyone who wasn't scheduled
for surgery was in here,
and they all just ran out of here
with the Director.
There's nobody else available.
Page anyway, get anyone at all.
Should I give it a try?
What?
This patient is laying on this table,
fighting for his life, and he's all alone.
I- Oh, I have to do something...
No, but... uh, there's too many
different things here.
You're just an intern,
you crazy son of a bitch!
Call a resident or higher right now!
There's no one else available,
there's nobody else...
There is someone else.
Vitals?
Blood pressure undetectable,
heart rate 170.
Alright, everyone, get ready to go.
Put your hands up.
I brought what you asked for.
Everyone, switch to those gloves
and change into new surgical gowns.
Turn up the ventilation
in the OR to the max.
- Give him epinephrine and dex, stat.
- On it.
You. Assist.
Yes, ma'am.
It stopped now.
Turn off the music.
BP is 120 over 65. Heart rate is 90.
Resuming surgery.
Tie 2-0 silk.
Off.
Scissors.
Tie.
Now off.
Sponge forceps.
Hold this.
Forceps.
Right angle.
Now hand me whatever you think I need.
If I need something else, I'll ask.
Understood, Doctor.
Bile duct ligation.
Her hands are quick, huh, Doctor?
It's a pleasure to meet you,
my name is Jang Hui-suk,
the head of Korea's
first locum tenens agency.
DIRECTOR JANG Hui-suk LOCUM TENENS AGENCY
I'll proudly say she's the agency's
most talented surgeon.
The great Doctor Gye Su-jeong,
general surgeon.
Specimen is out. Send it to pathology.
What's the gauze count?
The gauze count... looks correct.
Let's close him up.
SURGERY TIME, CURRENT TIME,
ANESTHESIA TIME
Blood loss?
- 200 cc.
- Before he wakes, inject hydrocortisone.
Injecting 100 milligrams
of hydrocortisone.
Let's wrap up.
Doctor Gye Su-jeong.
Thank you for your hard work.
Thanks for your hard work!
My goodness.
Doctor Bu, you're still in here?
Oh, I even left my phone in here.
I was so out of it.
Director Kim is alright now.
Our NS team, along with Doctor Bae,
are very good at what they do.
Well, that's a relief.
How on earth did that mad dog-
that Doctor Gye...
I just don't get it.
It was like she could tell...
What are you doing? Are you crazy?
What'd you inject him with? Huh?
Doctor! Look, look! He's breathing again!
Get a move on. Open up his blood vessels.
DIRECTOR JANG Hui-suk LOCUM TENENS AGENCY
Doctor Gye!
Okay, so... Doctor Gye Su-jeong
handled the operation, then?
Did you page her?
Are you trying to reprimand
Doctor Park Tae-gyeong right now?
How is it not a problem
no one else was there?
It was a very urgent emergency situation,
it was a high-risk scenario where
another patient needed our attention--
The Director clearly mattered more to you.
How could you abandon
your current patient?
What do you expect?
Are we supposed to abandon other patients?
Isn't Director Kim our patient now, too?
You should've left someone
behind to handle the surgery!
Hold on!
Doctor, what are you doing?
Put that bowl down right now!
Dr. Gye, you performed surgery without
permission to handle the operation.
You witnessed everyone panic
when Mr. Seo Byeong-gyu went into shock.
Right, it was from an "unknown cause"?
I think you know the cause.
You do know the cause, don't you?
Can you answer me now?
Stop eating that! Stop!
Give it a rest with the noodles.
You were there.
You were there, you were there.
What, you're all doctors, or am I wrong?
Think about it.
That injection..
it was epinephrine, wasn't it?
EPINEPHRINE:
TREATMENT FOR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
Why do you ignore me?
Oh, what now?
What?
Why are you staring? Why are you
mad-dogging me with that look? Huh?
Six o'clock!
Again? Not again. No way.
Was I standing under a clock again?
- Go! Go and catch her, bring her back!
- Yeah, will do.
An epinephrine injection?
But Director Kim had an ischemic stroke,
so why would she give him that?
When Su-jeong
was in the observation gallery,
she wanted to have
an MRI done on the Director.
She did?
I think she knew that the Director
was gonna go down.
ROOM 4210 SEO ******-GYU
"Go and bring her back"? Yeah, right.
You earned going home
early today, Doctor Gye.
GUSEO UNIVERSITY SEONAM MEDICAL CENTER
Doctor Do... Doctor Do.
Yes, sir?
Was it Doctor Gye... who did the surgery?
Ah... he's asking if it was you
that finished the operation.
Not again with the nodding.
- Uhh...
- Yes?
She did a good job,
and as expected, applying the MS technique
was the right call.
Ah. Okay.
"Good work", he said.
And, "As expected, the MS technique
after opening him up was the right call."
Actually, no. As expected,
open surgery was a mistake.
If you don't have anything else to relay,
I'll excuse myself.
Dr. Gye!
You're fired! You're... crazy!
The Director says,
"You're fired", and "You're crazy."
Did you catch that?
So, what entices a doctor
who hates doctors to work here?
I was just terminated.
Now, I'm going home.
No way, they fired her for that?
Miss Ju-hye.
But she saved that patient's life,
how could he just cut her loose like that?
- Doctor, stop.
- Let's eat, no more about this.
We said we'd come back once we were done.
Any doctor who knows how to operate
could've pulled off the surgery.
One-hundred percent, Sir.
This one time during a lecture,
the professor accidentally
played a surgery video at 1.5 times speed.
Everyone thought it was hilarious,
but now, it's not so funny if you see
someone operate faster than that for real.
Hey, how many surgeries
have you even seen, huh?
I can go through
a surgery that quick, too.
- Oh, is that so?
- -Mmm.
At that speed?
Did you watch the recording
of the operation?
Did you see us change our gloves?
That's why I was called in,
it was because of the gloves.
She said she wanted to use non-latex ones.
- A latex... allergy?
- A latex allergy?
Anaphylaxis.
How did she know?
I mean, the patient's pre-op questionnaire
didn't say anything about latex.
The rubber factory...
Not everyone who works around rubber, even
for years, gets a delayed-onset allergy.
But there was an allergen
present that triggered a reaction.
No, no, no, hold on a second.
So then, how'd she know?
The Director had a cerebral infarction,
how could she've known?
Hold on...
Maybe she drugged him earlier?
Look, just stop talking nonsense,
and finish eating.
She's been fired already, we're done.
How absurd that the doctor saying,
"She drugged the Director" is still here,
while the doctor who saved a life
just gets tossed out.
My goodness, this hospital is sideways.
Okay, that's enough, just give it a rest.
We're already on thin ice.
That allergy's why I can't be eating...
any tropical fruits or anything like this.
It's a relief to see that you're alright
and still with us, Director Kim.
Yeah.
Yes... I was there for the whole thing.
In fact, I was incredibly worried.
In the OR, it looked like nobody else
knew you were in anaphylactic shock.
Anaphylactic shock? What, how'd you...
Well, I stopped by your office
earlier this morning to say hi,
and happened to see an old melon
your receptionist threw out.
And during the surgery, I saw you keep
clawing at your neck, scratching an itch.
And among medical professionals,
a latex allergy surfacing later in life,
I wouldn't say it's uncommon, is it?
What latex allergy?
Oh, Director Kim.
Why would you do something like that?
Powdered gloves are banned in law.
Powder can get in the respiratory system
and cause anaphylaxis, among other things.
You ignored the risk nonetheless
for your own convenience, didn't you?
While a patient's life was on the line,
in your hands.
No, I- I didn't- I didn't know.
Oh, but of course you didn't know.
Because who could've known that either
of you had a latex allergy ahead of time?
Or that you'd have a reaction?
How many years have you been out of the OR
to not know something so simple?
The recording doesn't show anything,
don't worry, sir.
There's something else, though.
Even though you left, these stayed behind.
MAY EXACERBATE
LATEX-INDUCED ALLERGIC REACTIONS
I also happened to hear the locum tenens
agency had given a gift box to you.
The hospital still cut a check
to the temp doctor anyway,
meaning this didn't cost you at all
and still managed to line your pockets.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Just keep breathing, don't worry.
I only want one thing.
A single, small request.
- Thank you so much.
- Please get home safely.
Okay, Doctor,
thank you for everything you've done.
THE DIRECTOR WILL BE MAKING ROUNDS
PLEASE GET READY
Director Bu Seung-gwon
will now begin to make his rounds.
Sorry, excuse me.
DIRECTOR'S OFFICE
Thank you very much for requesting
Dr. Gye from our agency, Director.
We're grateful to have been selected.
Hold on, Director Bu...
I'll hand this to you,
this is the new contract we've drawn up.
Just a moment.
EMPLOYMENT CONTRACT
Wait, but...
We'll be requiring an eight-hour workday,
as well as compensation for overtime,
extra pay per surgery performed,
with nighttime surgeries
at twice the rate.
Take a look at the rate list.
So you're saying extra...
Uh, at these rates...
she would earn more than my salary.
I can't accept this, Director Bu.
Why not come work through
our agency as well, then, Doctor?
Could I raise something? Director,
if she botches it when operating,
we're the ones who'll end up being liable.
Doctor Gye Su-jeong won't do any work
that doesn't require a medical license.
No menial tasks.
There're many smaller tasks to be done
that the hospital especially depends on.
- That's the reason we hired you-
- Hold that thought.
For example, assisting attendings
with their research projects.
That is not something I do.
Doing research for attendings' papers.
Director rounds, attending rounds.
That is not something I do.
Company dinners, socializing,
events, taking part in pleasantries,
or talent shows, anything like that.
That is not something I do.
It's all written there, in the contract.
SPECIAL TERMS
Don't ever start to think...
those are things I will do.
What d’you expect to do, then?
What matters here,
is that Doctor Gye Su-jeong...
At no point will I allow...
any surgery to fail.
Uh, Director, one second, please?
You can start here today.
Thank you, Director.
You won't regret this decision.
I'm looking forward to
working with you, Doctor Gye Su-jeong.
Social pleasantries, when they occur,
are another thing I won't do.
You little-
Director. So, what I shared with you,
was it of good use to you?
Ah... yes.
Oh, then we'll settle
that some other occasion, Director.
Now, have a good day, everyone.
If I ever become
Become lonely
Uh, hold on. No, wait a minute!
Director, she won't add anything to help
build or secure the future you envisioned.
She boasts an impressive
and notable career.
Beyond that, she'll be
of great help to the hospital.
Oh, I mean, there are plenty
of doctors who also have-
Did you watch the entire
recording of her surgery?
I did.
In all these years, not once have I seen
anybody with the amount of speed she has.
I feel like someone else
should have this instead.
Ahh!
Why are we letting that snake back here?
What the hell is going on?
This is driving me crazy.
She rebukes being part of
the pack and despises standing authority.
There's a strong possibility...
she'll stop our whole structure
in its tracks completely.
RESUME NAME: GYE SU-JEONG
Dr. Gye Su-jeong!
Ah, here you go.
I noticed your name
hadn't been embroidered on it yet.
I also know why now.
Melon. Isn't that right?
When people with latex allergy eat fruit,
an allergic reaction can trigger.
He runs a rubber factory.
No, not those. Bring me the powdered ones.
The only weapons stored
in her arsenal are her medical license,
and the surgical skills
that she sharpened from bare metal.
Dr. Gye Su-jeong!
Gye Su-jeong!
Give us an answer for once.
Can't you hear us?
I said can't you hear us?
Hey, Snake Su-jeong! Snake Su-jeong!
Gye Su-jeong, general surgeon.
She can be easily gotten rid of
if she no longer meets our needs.
We can just put her in the can with
all the other issues this hospital has.
We'll let this play out a little longer,
we'll know soon enough.
You said you hated it here.
Why did you come back?
If you hate it so much, why'd you
become a doctor in the first place?
Also known as...
Doctor X.
IN MEMORY OF KIM HYUN-I,
OUR CHERISHED COLLEAGUE
DOCTOR X: MAFIA IN WHITE
- "Mad dog"?
- You don't have the skills.
Are we seriously working with her?
She's so annoying.
I don't want the operation.
- I object.
- Are you saying you can do it, Doctor Gye?
Just let me die!
You could die today, next week,
it makes no difference in the long run.
A surgeon who performs surgery
no matter what danger a patient may be in.
Now, this is more like it.
You can't go on forever
and never fail an operation.
You're a doctor!
You should look after
your patient until the end!